Information assurance and cyber security are greatly
involved with the risk management process.
The level of cyber security required depends on the level of risk.
The entity is willing to accept
that is the potential consequences of what's going on in our environment.
Once we evaluate this risk,
then we will implement security controls to mitigate
the risk to the level that we find acceptable
risks can be from cyber attacks such as malware,
social engineering or denial of service attacks
or from other situations that affect our environment such as fire,
violent crime or natural disasters
with well designed risk management technologies.
We can recognize vulnerabilities and threats and calculate the
likelihood and the potential impact of each threat.